<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on Tetrate Istio Distro | Simple, safe enterprise-grade Istio</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on Tetrate Istio Distro | Simple, safe enterprise-grade Istio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2021 Tetrate</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is GetIstio - Inaugural Community Meetup</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/getistio-inaugural/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/getistio-inaugural/</guid><description>Feb 18, 2021 at AM 9:00 PST Check your timezone Recording: https://youtu.be/EGzvJK0pzx8 The inaugural meetup will be a special edition with 90 minutes to introduce the community, unpack the GetIstio and GetEnvoy projects, and hear what&amp;rsquo;s new in the Istio 1.9 release. We look forward to diving into the topics, demonstrating some new Istio capabilities and answering all of your questions during the Q&amp;amp;A session.</description></item><item><title>IstioCon 2021</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/istiocon-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/istiocon-2021/</guid><description>IstioCon 2021 is a community-led event, showcasing the lessons learned from running Istio in production, hands-on experiences from the Istio community, and featuring maintainers from across the Istio ecosystem. The conference offers a mix of keynotes, technical talks, lightning talks, workshops, and roadmap sessions. Fun and games are also included with two social hours to take the load off and mesh with the Istio community, vendors, and maintainers!
We are excited to launch IstioCon as a new way for Istio community members to gather, connect, and share information.</description></item><item><title>Effortless Envoy and WASM with GetEnvoy</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/getenvoy-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/getenvoy-deep-dive/</guid><description> Mar 4, 2021 at AM 9:00 PST Check your timezone Recording: https://youtu.be/mauuUWrxpdk Episode 01 of the community launches into the broader Istio ecosystem with a look into Envoy and how, like GetIstio, the GetEnvoy project helps ensure success on any cloud or platform. Christoph Pakulski will be showing off the power of WASM and how Istio and Envoy are better together.
Welcome and Introduction Community news Future topics Community resources GetEnvoy Envoy overview GetEnvoy CLI GetEnvoy demo GetEnvoy roadmap Q&amp;amp;A Closing with resource links Join here</description></item><item><title>Istio the Easy Way with GetIstio</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/getistio-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/getistio-deep-dive/</guid><description> Mar 18, 2021 at AM 9:00 PDT Check your timezone Recording: https://youtu.be/Q5MQjwUpay0 Episode 02 of the community meetup dives into getmesh gen-ca to help integrate Istio with intermediate certificate authorities (CA). GetIstio will do more than CA integration by managing the installation, operations, and upgrade of Istio across clouds. Join us as we dive into Istio the Easy Way!
Welcome and Introduction Community news Future topics Community resources GetIstio GetIstio CLI GetIstio demo GetIstio roadmap getmesh gen-ca Generate intermediate CA from different managed services Q&amp;amp;A Closing with resource links Join here</description></item><item><title>SSL Certificates in Istio Ingress Gateway</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-003/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 11:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-003/</guid><description>May 27, 2021 at AM 11:00 PDT Check your timezone Recording: https://youtu.be/nYJJ57WCkxE In episode 3, we will talk about how to set up SSL certificates in your Istio ingress gateway. We’ll show you how to use self-signed certificates (and why you should never do this) and how to automate certificate management.
Demo script for all scenarios is here.</description></item><item><title>Deploying multiple Istio ingress gateways</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-004/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 11:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-004/</guid><description> Jun 10, 2021 at AM 11:00 PDT Check your timezone In episode 4, we will talk about how to deploy multiple Istio ingress gateways. Running more than one Istio ingress gateway allows for more complex scenarios. For example, running a separate internal gateway and a public gateway, or running separate gateways based on the hosts.
Join here</description></item><item><title>Istio Big Talk Episode 4</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-006/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-006/</guid><description>Jun 23, 2021 at AM 8:00 CST Check your timezone Topic: How to used Istio in a large scale production environment Guest: Peng Chen(陈鹏) from Baidu. He is a R&amp;amp;D engineer, is now working in the Cloud Native team of Baidu Infrastructure Department. He has led and participated in the large-scale implementation of Service Mesh in many core businesses within Baidu, and has</description></item><item><title>Security in Istio</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-005/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-005/</guid><description> Jun 24, 2021 at AM 11:00 PDT Check your timezone In episode 5, we will talk about Security in Istio. You’ll learn about the difference between authentication and authorization. We’ll show you how to enable mutual TLS with peer authentication, use request authentication with Auth0, and how to control access to your workloads with the authorization policies.
Join here</description></item><item><title>Istio Big Talk Episode 5</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-007/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-007/</guid><description> Jun 30, 2021 at AM 8:00 CST Check your timezone Tetrate is hosting Istio Big Talk, discussing Istio Best Practices on Tencent Cloud with Jimmy Song and guest Hua Zhong on Bilibili.
Join here</description></item><item><title>Istio Weekly Episode 6: Envoy Fundamentals</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-008/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0730</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-008/</guid><description> Jul 8, 2021 at AM 11:00 PDT Check your timezone Envoy is one part of the engine that keeps Istio running. How does Envoy work? What are listeners, clusters, and endpoints?
Join us on July 8th for another Istio weekly episode where we&amp;rsquo;ll introduce the fundamentals of Envoy proxy.
Join here</description></item><item><title>Episode 07: Developing Envoy Wasm Extensions</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-009/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0730</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-009/</guid><description>Jul 22, 2021 at AM 11:00 PST Check your timezone WebAssembly (Wasm) and the Envoy Proxy Wasm SDK are a way to extend the Envoy proxy functionality. We&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use the Proxy Wasm Go SDK and the func-e CLI to develop and test your Wasm extensions.
Join us on July 22th for another Istio weekly episode where we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how to start developing Envoy Wasm extensions.</description></item><item><title>Istio in the enterprise: Solving security and scale challenges for microservices in Kubernetes</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-010/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0730</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-010/</guid><description>Aug 4, 2021 at AM 1:00 EDT Check your timezone Join experts from Mirantis and Tetrate as they guide you through some of the challenges of deploying, managing and scaling microservices in enterprise. We’ll cover why and how Istio helps address these challenges from a customer perspective.
As container-based applications and Kubernetes are widely being adopted by enterprises, customers face multiple challenges on how to manage large number of microservices based applications in a multi-cluster environment.</description></item><item><title>Episode 08: External CA with Istio</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-011/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0730</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-011/</guid><description> Aug 5, 2021 at AM 11:00 PDT Check your timezone Istio CA generates a self-signed root certificate and key and uses them to sign all workload certificates. In this episode, we’ll show you how to configure Istio to use an external CA to distribute certificates.
Join us on August 5th for another Istio weekly episode where we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how to configure external CA with Istio.
Join here</description></item><item><title>Episode 09: Customizing Istio metrics</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-012/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-012/</guid><description> Aug 19, 2021 at AM 11:00 PDT Check your timezone Join us on August 19th for another Istio weekly episode where we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how to customize and create new service-level metrics.
Join here</description></item><item><title/><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-013/</guid><description> Sep 2, 2021 at AM 11:00 PST Check your timezone Join us on August 19th for another Istio weekly episode where we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how to customize and create new service-level metrics.
Join here</description></item><item><title>Access Control for Microservices</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-016/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-016/</guid><description>Nov 18, 2021 at AM 11:00 PST Check your timezone Join us on November 18th for the next Istio weekly episode where we&amp;rsquo;ll talk with Tetrate&amp;rsquo;s founding engineer, Ignasi Barrera.
Ignasi leads the development of a modern security solution for the hybrid and multi-cloud worlds, based on NGAC - Next Generation Access Control. In this episode, we’ll talk about access control for microservices and we’ll explain what NGAC is and why it matters to you.</description></item><item><title>Episode 11: Enterprise service mesh and why you need it</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-014/</guid><description> Sep 16, 2021 at AM 11:00 PST Check your timezone Join us on September 16th for another Istio weekly episode where we’ll talk to Adam Zwickey, director of global solutions engineering at Tetrate. Adam will talk about scenarios that call for an enterprise service mesh, such as TSB. He’ll show us how TSB can help us manage and configure service meshes in enterprise environments.
Join here</description></item><item><title>Episode 12: How I started contributing to Istio and Envoy</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-015/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-015/</guid><description>Oct 1, 2021 at PM 4:00 PST Check your timezone Join us on October 1st for the next Istio weekly episode where we&amp;rsquo;ll talk with Istio maintainer Aditya Prerepa.
In addition to being a member of the Istio networking working group, Aditya is also finishing high school this year. He’s worked on Istio for more than a year with a focus on Pilot and xDS as well as VM health checking, auto registration, and multitenancy.</description></item><item><title>Episode 15: Setting up Istio with external control plane</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-018/</guid><description>Dec 9, 2021 at AM 11:00 PST Check your timezone Join us on December 9th for the next Istio weekly episode, where we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to install Istio with an external control plane.
The external control plane deployment model offers a clean separation between mesh operators and mesh administrators. Mesh operators install and manage Istio’s control plane on one cluster and then connect one or more remote clusters (data planes) to form a mesh.</description></item><item><title>Istio's new Wasm-based extension mechanism and ecosystem</title><link>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://istio.tetratelabs.io/community/event/tid-episode-017/</guid><description> Nov 24, 2021 at PM 4:00 PST Check your timezone Join us on November 24th for the next Istio weekly episode where we&amp;rsquo;ll talk with Tetrate software engineer and Envoy proxy and Proxy Wasm maintainer Takeshi Yoneda.
In this episode, Takeshi will give us an overview of WebAssembly (Wasm) in Istio and talk about exciting new Wasm-related features he worked on for the Istio 1.12 release.
Join here</description></item></channel></rss>